Raj Shah

github.com/shahraj1 Boston, MA

shahraj603@gmail.com LinkedIn: Raj-513-620-9801

SUMMARY

A highly skilled IT professional with 3 years of coding experience, including college and side projects, and 2.5 years in the financial consulting industry. Experienced in application development, support, and building RESTful APIs, with some front-end projects. Have a track record of delivering successful projects on time, including a challenging 6-month project completed in just 3 months, showcasing exceptional time management and problem-solving skills. As the sole owner and developer of a proprietary financial application, I bring solid C# and SQL knowledge to efficiently develop, enhance, and maintain software for complex financial scenarios.

EDUCATION

Northeastern University
B.Sc. Information technology

Boston, MA Graduation - 2022

Cincinnati State Technical Community College

Cincinnati, OH

A.S. in Software Engineering Technology

Completion - 2019

EXPERIENCE

Meketa Investment Group Financial Consulting Firm

Westwood, MA

Application Developer and Support Specialist (Corporate Promotion)

Dec 2022 - Present

- · **Application Owner**: Develop, enhance, and maintain an in-house legacy-built portfolio management application that houses data for all clients, plans, and investment information.
- Importing Tool: Created a dynamic importer in C# to speed manual data loads for CSVs, texts, and Excel files by validating and saving the files directly into the database decreasing the number of Ad-hoc requests.
- **Performance Enhancement**: Reduced operating speed from ten minutes to one and a half minutes, increasing the performance by 85% of the application by refactoring the WCF service call only to get the required information.
- · **Project Separation**: Assisted in breaking out a Visual Studio Solution of 52 projects into its own separate NuGet packages allowing each solution to be individually deployed and referenced. The solution also got moved from TFVC to Git which implemented pull Requests.
- · **APIs**: Build RESTful APIs that serve data that parsed and provided over 50,000 clients, plans, and products with performance returns for a public-facing web application.
- Integration Tool: Build a web application for generic mapping using Angular that allows users to map two entities from different systems by updating custom foreign key references using POST APIs.
- · System Integration: Integrated a new system into an existing one by creating new UI controls on the application and implementing the necessary GETs and POSTs data calls using Windows Communication Foundation(WCF)
- Data Integration: Build a new Visual Studio Control Flow using SQL to maintain integration between the in-house database and Dynamic 365 CRM for one entity that upserts the destination table with only modified changes.

Welly's Wellness Mobile Retail Startup

Marina Del Rey, CA

 $Project\ Manager\ \&\ Lead\ Developer\ -\ Part\text{-}Time\ (Remote\ -\ concurrent\ with\ Meketa\ job)$

Jan 2022 - Sept 2022

- \cdot Leadership: Led a team of seven to enhance and modify Welly's wellness website.
- · Documentation: Created Product Charter, Work breakdown structure, and UAT documentation for stakeholders.
- Management: Utilized Jira tool to streamline project management, ensuring efficient monitoring and effective communication of product delivery to both the product owner and stakeholders in an agile environment.
- · Backup & Testing: Set up daily backup for the site and created staging and testing environment for development using cPanel.
- · **Security**: Updated the WordPress website and the plugins to the most current version and verified the payment compliance requirements were met.

Meketa Investment Group Financial Consulting Firm

Application Support Specialist (Corporate Promotion)

Nov 2021 - Nov 2022

Westwood, MA

- Security: Worked with OWASP ZAP and Sonar-Cloud tool to remediate critical severity risk and created unit tests with assertions for an existing application increasing the test coverage of one application from 30% to 100%.
- ETL: Implemented a unit test using MS Test Framework in C# that reads data from CSV, and Excel files for a series of returns that validates over 4000 records and modifies the database for any updates.
- · Azure Pipelines: Create and configure CI/CD Pipelines to build and deploy desktop applications, web apps, and Web API solutions built in C# base.
- · Caching: Create and implement Redis Cache in Azure to improve API performance that leverages high volumes of data.
- IIS Configuration: Set up web hosting app services and sites in Windows servers and Azure to set up production and testing environments for all existing and new applications.
- · **Support**: Monitored and managed a support queue for production bugs, issues, code enhancement, and any Ad-hoc requests.
- **Documentation:** Created exception reports using Power-BI and build FAQs to address frequent production bugs and issues decreasing the number of incoming tickets.

IT Intern

Full-Time

Westwood, MA

Jul 2021 - Oct 2021

- · Laptop Deployment: Achieved the company's 2021 goal of deploying 70 domain-joined laptops, imaging, and setting up laptops, to support remote and hybrid workplace environments for employees.
- Help Desk and Infrastructure: Maintained IT resources by setting up workstations and providing user support via Help Desk for on-site and remote users.

Krishi Inc Retail-chain Company

Erlanger, KY

Software Engineer Intern - Full-time

Jan 2019 - Jun 2019

- · Software: Worked in a team to build a Point of Sale (POS) system for a small business chain using Visual Basic.NET Programming as a front-end supporting an MS SQL Server Database.
- · New Database Setup: Helped client migrate their database from an outdated format to a SQL server database.
- · Testing: Created test cases, with assertions and UAT processes for unit and integration testing in a scrum environment.
- · Setup: Assisted client set up the new system, collaborating, and training individual personnel where needed.

SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Visual Basic .NET, C#, C++, Java, HTML, CSS, PHP, JavaScript, and Python
- Frontend / Backend: Angular, Node, Windows Forms, REST API
- Databases: SQL Server, MySQL, Azure SQL Database
- Tools: Visual Studio, VS Code, Azure DevOps, Jira, Power BI
- Version Control: Team Foundation Version Control (TFVC), Git

Related Certificates

- The Developers Guide to Python 3 Programming: Learn fundamentals of Python 3 [March 2021].
- Become a Certified Web Developer: Technologies covers: HTML5 and CSS3; JavaScript and jQuery; XML, JSON and Ajax; PHP and MySQL; Yii Framework[April 2021].
- WordPress 5 Training: Learn fundamentals on Pages, Posts, blocks, plugins, and staging WordPress Sites. [April 2022].